so about around four years ago I I wrote
about this exercise in my glute ebook
and then I've never talked about it
since it's the band standing hip thrust
and it's a pretty effective exercise um
like I said I wrote about it four years
ago and I don't know why I never have
never filmed a video or never written an
article about it but it's pretty good
and I think you'll like it notice uh
this is a pretty narrow power rack it's
you know a pretty cheap or affordable
power a so these are narrow this helps
if you do this in your gym you might
have to toy around with the band tension
if you have to walk out further but
notice the setup here I have just the
pegs facing backwards and I have the
band secured around so I am going to
climb over
it just like this and notice if I'm
standing I have the bands just a little
a little bit lower than you know my my
hips because I'm going to sink back so I
will place the bands at my hips okay I
will walk out I will hold on to the
bands so from here I'm going to push my
feet forward so see my shins right now
they're kind of at a negative angle my
uh tibia here is vertical here I'm
sitting back so far so this is the
starting SP position you're sitting back
your arms are extended and then from
here I'm just going to do like a like a
hip thrust and I'm going to I'm not
going to go explosively I'm going to
squeeze sit
back now I don't want to pull myself
with the arms so much as push forward
with the hips but you will notice
yourself pulling a little bit with the
arms
now you might want to finish about right
here but push those glutes further and
squeeze hold the end for about 3 seconds
so one 2
3 one 2 three and you will notice a lot
of end range hip extension torque with
this exercise so it
compliments squats and Goa squats and L
and deas that build strength more in
this range and this exercise will build
strength more in this range so this
makes it um in the same category as
barbell hip thrust back extensions um
anyway give it a try I think you're
going to like it